(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
聞こえるか
Can you hear it?
復活のイデオン
Resurrection of Ideon
聞こえるだろう
You can hear it, right?
はるかな
From far away...
とどろき
...the roar.
闇の中 心ゆさぶる
In the darkness, shaking the heart...
目覚めはじまる
...the awakening begins.
大地わりそそり立つ姿
A figure splitting the earth and standing tall...
正義のあかし(あかし)か
...is it the sign of justice?
伝説の巨人の力
The power of the legendary giant...
銀河切りさく
...tears through the galaxy.
おたけびが電光石火の
A roar, like a bolt of lightning...
一撃を呼ぶ
...calls forth a single strike.
ふるえる瞳 こらせよ
Focus your trembling eyes!
復活のとき
The time for resurrection!
人よ 命よ
O humans, O life...
始まりを見る
...witness the beginning.
Space runaway Ideon (Ideon)
Ideon, Ideon
戦うか
Will you fight?
戦えるか
Can you fight?
おびえる
Trembling...
心よ
...heart.
せまりくる悪の力に
Against the approaching forces of evil...
勇気を示せ
...show your courage!
空に飛ぶかがやく姿
A shining figure flying in the sky...
命の叫びか
...is it the cry of life?
伝説の巨人の力
The power of the legendary giant...
銀河切りさく
...tears through the galaxy.
必殺のわざが宇宙を
A deadly technique across the universe...
闇へと変える
...turns it into darkness.
おそれぬ瞳 ひらけよ
Open your fearless eyes!
復活のとき
The time for resurrection!
人よ 命よ
O humans, O life...
ちからを見る
...witness the power.
Space runaway Ideon (Ideon)
Ideon, Ideon
好き好き大好き
Suki Suki Daisuki
常識をはるかに超えて
Thoughts that grow
つのる想い
far beyond common sense
突然変異的に勃発した
A rose-colored love
バラ色の恋
that broke out like a mutation
もはや暴力的とも言える程の
A pure love so intense
純愛
it could almost be called violent
既に昭和史に刻む勢いの
A 'Je t'aime' with enough momentum
ジュテーム
to be carved into Showa history
Kiss me 殴るように
Kiss me, until blood seeps from my lips
唇に血が滲む程
as if I'd been struck
Hold me あばらが音を立てて
Hold me, until my ribs
折れる程
crack and break
好き好き大好き
Love you, love you, I love you so much
愛してるって言わなきゃ殺す
Say you love me, or I'll kill you
日常を打破して
Eros that breaks through daily life
具体化するエロス
and takes form
本能で重ねる情事
Affairs layered by instinct,
無限地獄
an infinite hell
アンチニヒリズムの
The intuitive recognition of
直感認識は
anti-nihilism is...
潜在的幼児性暴力癖を
triggering latent infantile
誘発
violent tendencies
Kiss me 殴るように
Kiss me, until blood seeps from my lips
唇に血が滲む程
as if I'd been struck
Hold me あばらが音を立てて
Hold me, until my ribs
折れる程
crack and break
好き好き大好き
Love you, love you, I love you so much
愛してるって言わなきゃ殺す
Say you love me, or I'll kill you
Kiss me 殴るように
Kiss me, until blood seeps from my lips
唇に血が滲む程
as if I'd been struck
Hold me あばらが音を立てて
Hold me, until my ribs
折れる程
crack and break
好き好き大好き
Love you, love you, I love you so much
いつでもフフフカビィ
Always, fufu, Kirby,
星のカビィ
Kirby of the Stars
けどほんとうは つよいよ
But he's actually strong,
ほんとうかな
I wonder if it's true?
ふしぎなちからを もつ
A legendary hero
でんせつのヒロ
with mysterious powers
つよいほしのせんし
A strong star warrior,
やるもんだカビィ
you've got this, Kirby!
へいわな らくえん
In a peaceful paradise,
だれかがおとしたなみだ
tears someone shed
わるいゆめなんか たべてしまいましょう
Let's eat up all those bad dreams
なくしたえがおを とりもどしにゆく
Going to get back the smiles we lost
そらからおちてくる ほしのちからを
Sucking up all the star power
いっぱいにすって
falling from the sky
まんまるピンクだよ
He's a round pink guy,
星のカビィ
Kirby of the Stars
けどなんにでも なれるよ
But he can become anything,
ほんとうかな
I wonder if it's true?
むげんのちからを もつ
A legendary hero
でんせつのヒロ
with infinite powers
つよいほしのせんし
A strong star warrior,
たのんだよカビィ
we're counting on you, Kirby!
カービィ★マーチ
Kirby March
幸せ楽園
Happy paradise
なぜだか邪魔が入るよ
For some reason, there's an interruption
悩みの種なら
If it's a cause for worry
食べてしまいましょう
Let's just eat it up
忘れた気持ちを
The feelings I forgot
取り戻しに行く
Going to get them back
空から落ちてくる星の力をいっぱい吸って
Inhaling plenty of the power of the stars falling from the sky
本当に強かった星のカービィ
He was truly strong, Kirby of the Stars
ねぇ友達になれたらなれるかな
Hey, I wonder if we can become friends
ヒーローらしくもない食いしん坊ヒーロー
A gluttonous hero who doesn't even act like a hero
強い星の戦士
A strong star warrior
見せてくれカービィ
Show us, Kirby
ぷよん
Puyon
はい！ということで、みんな来てくれてありがとう！
Yes! So, thank you all for coming!
コメント見てるよ！
I'm watching the comments!
あ、復活のイデオン。好き好き大好き。
Oh, Ideon: Be Invoked. Love it, love it, love it.
で、カービィ★マーチを...
And, "Kirby March"...
ちょっとあれだね、3曲連続だとあれだね...
It's a bit much, three songs in a row is...
息切れしちゃって、すいません。
I'm a bit out of breath, sorry.
カービィ★マーチを聴いてもらいました。ありがとうございます。
You just heard "Kirby March". Thank you very much.
でね、今日のステージはこちら。
And the stage for today is this one.
あの、ダイナーがね、コンセプトとなっておりますので...
Um, the concept is a diner...
ころねが途中で食べちゃったんだけどね。
Korone ate part of it though.
この、細犬バーガーとかも結構凝って作ってあるので...
This Hosoinu Burger is also made with a lot of detail,
スクショ撮ってください。
so please take some screenshots.
でね、撮ったスクショは今日のハッシュタグは...
And for the screenshots you take, today's hashtag is...
戌神ころね生誕祭2022で、Twitterに投稿していただけると...
#戌神ころね生誕祭2022, if you could post them on Twitter,
とっても嬉しいです。
I'd be very happy.
でね、カービィ★マーチ、一人で歌ったんだけど...
And, I sang "Kirby March" by myself, but...
やっぱりこれね、マーチは誰かと歌いたいなと思ってますけど...
as I thought, for a march, I'd like to sing with someone...
誰かいたかな？
I wonder if anyone's here?
あ、あの子なら多分一緒に歌ってくれると思うから、ちょっと行ってくる！
Oh, I think that girl would probably sing with me, so I'll go get her!
みんな、ちょっとこのまま待ってて。待っててね。
Everyone, please wait here. Wait for me, okay?
ケロッ！とマーチ / 作詞：もりちよこ 作曲：沢田完
Kero!tto March / Lyrics: Chiyoko Mori / Composition: Kan Sawada
ケロッ、ケロッ、ケロッ
Kero, kero, kero
いざ進め！
Forward we march!
地球侵略せよ
Invade the Earth!
ケッケロ、ケッケロ、ケッケロ
Kekkero, kekkero, kekkero
傘持って
Carry your umbrella
出かけた日にゃ、いつも晴れ
On days you go out, it's always sunny
気をつけ！ 目を食いしばれ！
Attention! Grit your eyes!
カレーのライスを炊き忘れ
Forgot to cook the rice for the curry
閉まるドア、小指はさんだ
Pinky finger caught in the closing door
飛び乗ったら行き先違う
Jumped on a train, heading the wrong way
社員旅行は、ケロンのみ
Company trip, Keronians only
あ、買った方が安いね晩御飯のおかず
Ah, it's cheaper to buy side dishes for dinner
ピロッ、ピロッ、ピロッ
Piro, piro, piro
突撃は！
Charge!
動く歩道で行け
Go on the moving walkway!
ピピロッ、ピピロッ、ピピロッ
Pipiro, pipiro, pipiro
早寝して
Go to bed early
寝坊して、また二度寝する
Oversleep, then sleep in again
全体！ 止まれ！ 回れ、お手！
Squad! Halt! Turn around, give paw!
嫌われたいのに愛される
Wanting to be hated, yet being loved
いらないもの買った、在庫の山
Bought things I don't need, a mountain of stock
欲しいものあるときゃ金がない
When I want something, I have no money
四の五の言えよ、ペコポン人
Keep on whining, Pekoponians!
お雷鳴っても、隠すヘソがない
Even if it thunders, I have no belly button to hide
熱きこの血潮と、胸に刻まれし闘魂
This hot blood, and the fighting spirit carved in my chest
永遠に勝ち誇れ、我らがケロン
Triumph forever, our Keron
熱きこの血潮と、胸に刻まれし闘魂
This hot blood, and the fighting spirit carved in my chest
永遠に勝ち誇れ、美しき星よ
Triumph forever, beautiful star
我らがケロン
Our Keron
全体！ 止まっちゃダメ！
Squad! Don't stop!
アウー！
Awoo!
ケロッ、ケロッ、ケロッ
Kero, kero, kero
高らかに
Loud and clear
勝利の...
Victory...
...だっけっぴっわ
...dakkepi-wa
ケッゲロゲ
Ke-geroge
張り切って
With all our might
電話に出たら
When I answer the phone
ファクシミリ
It's a facsimile
平成は本日よりケロロ元年であります
From today, the Heisei era is the first year of Keroro!
四角いところは丸く掃け
Sweep the square corners into circles
水かき合わせてギッペソギ
Clap your webbed hands together, gippesogi
歯磨きならイチゴの香り
If you're brushing teeth, go for strawberry scent
ケロンは宇宙一だぽ
Keron is number one in the universe, po
合い言葉はホホゥ 実は十五分
The password is 'Hohou', actually fifteen minutes
そんじゃそんじゃそんじゃどっかりさー
Then, then, then, let's settle down
ゲロゲロ ゲロゲロ ゲロ
Gero-gero, gero-gero, gero
ゲロ！
Gero!
こよりー！
Koyori!
ころね先輩ー！
Korone-senpai!
来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming!
いえ、こちらこそ呼んで...あれ？呼んでいただいて...
No, thank YOU for invi... wait, for inviting me...
呼んでっていうか、これ、こよりのさ、故郷じゃない？
Well, more than inviting, isn't this your hometown?
そうなんです！
That's right!
なんとサバンナにお越しいただきまして...
Thank you so much for visiting the savanna...
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
あのね、めっちゃ迷った。
You know, I got super lost.
来るまでにめっちゃ迷ったけどね。
I got really lost on my way here.
あ、地図書いたはずなんですけどね、
Ah, I thought I'd drawn a map,
分かりづらかったですかね？
was it hard to follow?
うーん、めっちゃ分かりづらかった！
Yeah, it was super confusing!
迷い所多かったけど、
There were many places to get lost,
うん。
but yeah.
来てくれてありがとうございます。
Thank you for coming.
あーい、とんでもないよ。
No problem at all.
せっかく故郷来ていただいたから...
Since you've come all the way to my hometown...
そうだね。
Right.
写真撮っちゃいます？
Shall we take a photo?
え、じゃあみんなスクショ、
Oh, then everyone, please
いっぱい撮ってね！
take lots of screenshots!
撮ってください。
Please take some.
何がいいか...どんなポーズがいいですかね？
What's good... what kind of pose should we do?
あ、サバンナっぽく、
Ah, something savanna-like,
ガオー！
Roar!
ちょっとサバンナがリアルすぎて...
The savanna is a bit too realistic...
ガオー！
Roar!
ガルルル...
Grrr...
え、何、こよりどうしたの？
Wait, what's wrong, Koyori?
やばい、ころね先輩...
Oh no, Korone-senpai...
こより野生が戻っちゃうかもしれません！
My wild instincts might be returning!
あ、ころね先輩逃げて！逃げて！
Ah, Korone-senpai, run! Run!
うわぁー！
Waaa!
え、ごめん。
Oh, sorry.
倒しちまった。
I knocked her over.
ガルルル...
Grrr...
ガブー...
Chomp...
GO-GO たまごっち！
GO-GO Tamagotchi!
いっせーの！
One, two, three!
たまご たまご たまごっち
Tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi
素直ち 友達
Sunaocchi, friends
たまご たまご たまごっち
Tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi
きっちり ぱっちり ピポパっち
Kicchiri, pacchiri, Pipopacchi
たまご たまご たまごっち
Tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi
毎日 大吉
Every day is lucky
たまご たまご たまごっち
Tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi
レッツゴー！ (イェーイ!) はしゃごー！ (イェーイ!) たまごっち (イェーイ!)
Let's go! (Yay!) Let's have fun! (Yay!) Tamagotchi! (Yay!)
毎日 僕ら 腰を回すよ
Every day we move our hips
くるくる たまもり みたいに
Round and round like a Tamamori
毎日 僕ら 夢を追うよ
Every day we chase our dreams
明日への手紙 みたいにさね
Like a letter to tomorrow
へこんだ時こそ 独りじゃないここ
When you're down, you're not alone here
見つけるチャンス 超ラキラキ
A chance to find, super lucky-lucky
たまとも 会いに行くぜ
Tamatomo, I'm coming to see you
いっせーの！
One, two, three!
たまご たまご たまごっち
Tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi
素直ち 友達
Sunaocchi, friends
たまご たまご たまごっち
Tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi
ピンチに ばっちり ベリマッチ
Perfectly in a pinch, very much
たまご たまご たまごっち
Tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi
毎日 大吉
Every day is lucky
たまご たまご たまごっち
Tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi
レッツゴー！ (イェーイ!) はしゃごー！ (イェーイ!) たまごっち (イェーイ!)
Let's go! (Yay!) Let's have fun! (Yay!) Tamagotchi! (Yay!)
それぞれ みんな キャラが違うよ
Each and everyone has a different character
寂しがり屋も 君もいるね
Lonely types and you are here too
それぞれ みんな 望み違うよ
Each and everyone has different wishes
欲しい物だって いいのいいのさ
Whatever you want is okay, it's okay
パッと目をとじて 手をつないだなら
If you close your eyes and hold hands
フレンドきらり 超ハッピーハッピー
Friend sparkles, super happy-happy
優しさ 同じだぜ
Our kindness is the same
いっせーの！
One, two, three!
たまご たまご たまごっち
Tamago, tamago, Tamagotchi
素直ち 友達
Sunaocchi, friends
いきてるってことは... ないちゃったあとの
Living means... after having cried...
えがおさがしさ... みつけようたまとも
looking for a smile... let's find a Tama-tomo.
いっしょに...
Together...
いっせーの たまごたまごたまごっち
One, two, egg egg Tamagotchi!
たまともだち
Tama-friend.
たまごたまごたまごっち ぴっちり ぱっちり べりーまっち
Egg egg Tamagotchi, pitchiri patchiri very much!
たまごたまごたまごっち まいにち だいじに
Egg egg Tamagotchi, cherishing every day.
たまごたまごたまごっち たまごたまごたまごっち
Egg egg Tamagotchi, egg egg Tamagotchi!
Ready go! (Yeah!) はじけろ (Yeah!) たまごっち (Yeah!)
Ready go! (Yeah!) Burst out! (Yeah!) Tamagotchi! (Yeah!)
たまごたまごたまごっち たまともだち
Egg egg Tamagotchi, Tama-friend.
たまごたまごたまごっち ぴっちり ぱっちり わたし
Egg egg Tamagotchi, pitchiri patchiri me!
たまごたまごたまごっち あちこち よりみち
Egg egg Tamagotchi, detouring here and there.
たまごたまごたまごっち たまごたまごたまごっち
Egg egg Tamagotchi, egg egg Tamagotchi!
いそごー！(Yeah!) しゅうごー！(Yeah!) たまごっち (Yeah!)
Let's hurry! (Yeah!) Assemble! (Yeah!) Tamagotchi! (Yeah!)
たまごっち！(Yeah!)
Tamagotchi! (Yeah!)
イェーイ！たまごたまごたまごっち！
Yay! Egg egg Tamagotchi!
みんなありがとうねー！
Thank you everyone!
こっち転びそうになったりとかしなかった？大丈夫？
Did you almost fall or anything? Are you okay?
あ、大丈夫、大丈夫なんだよ、ちょっと
Ah, I'm fine, I'm fine, really.
なんか雑だったけどｗ
You seemed a bit rough though lol.
ちなみにこのたまご...
By the way, these eggs...
え？大丈夫っしょ！
Eh? It's fine, right!
なあに？
What is it?
なにかわかんないけどさ、このたまご渡されたけど一体何のたまごなの？
I don't know what it is, but we were given these eggs. What kind of eggs are they?
いや、それはね、いいじゃないですか、別にいいよ！
Well, that's... it's fine, isn't it? It doesn't matter!
じゃあたまごを持ってさ、写真撮影しようよ！
Then, let's hold the eggs and take a photo!
あ、いいねー！
Oh, that sounds good!
あ、みんな柄が...
Oh, everyone's pattern is...
そうなんだよ！おかゆとフブちゃんとミオしゃのとね
That's right! Yours, Okayu, Fubuki-chan, and Mio-sha's.
うおー、すごい！たまごー！イェーイ！
Whoa, amazing! Eggs! Yay!
いっぱい撮ってー！
Take lots of pictures!
撮っしょ撮っしょ撮っしょ撮っしょ
Snap snap snap snap!
いやー、いいよね。何のたまごなんだろうね、本当にね
Yeah, it's nice. I wonder what kind of eggs they are, really.
え、気になる。これめちゃめちゃ気になるよ
I'm curious. I'm really curious about this.
これあれだね、色誰か塗ったの？それとも天然？
By the way, did someone paint these colors? Or are they natural?
多分塗ったんだと思うよ。
I think they were probably painted.
あ、塗ったんだｗ
Ah, painted lol.
元々は同じ色だったと思うんだけど。
I think they were originally the same color though.
あ、なんかちょっと、ころさんのたまご透けてるみたい... え？
Ah, wait, Koro-san's egg looks a bit transparent... eh?
え？
Eh?
なになにこれ？
What is this?
え、なんかうちのたまご...
Eh, something's in my egg...
カマキリ？
A mantis?
カマキリ！？
A mantis!?
え、カマキリ！？
Eh, a mantis!?
と思いきや、なんか無数のころねすきーが入っとる！
I thought so, but it's filled with countless Korone-sukis!
えー！ころねすきー！？
Eh! Korone-sukis!?
マツケンサンバⅡ
Matsuken Samba II
叩けボンゴ 響けサンバ 踊れ南のカルナバル
Strike the bongo, let the samba ring out, dance the southern carnival.
誰も彼も 浮かれ騒ぎ 光る汗がはじけ飛ぶ
Everyone is in a festive mood, shining sweat is flying.
熱い風に 体あずけ 心ゆくまで踊れば
Entrust your body to the hot wind, and dance to your heart's content.
波も歌うよ 愛のサンバを 胸にあふれるこのリズム
Even the waves sing a samba of love, this rhythm overflowing in my heart.
オーレ！オレ！ マツケンサンバ！
Ole! Ole! Matsuken Samba!
あぁ恋せよアミーゴ 踊ろうセニョリータ
Ah, fall in love, amigo, let's dance, senorita.
眠りさえ忘れて 踊り明かそう
Forget even sleep and dance the night away
サンバ ビバ サンバ
Samba, viva Samba
マツ・ゲン・サンバ
Matsu-ken Samba
オレ！
Ole!
町はボンゴ 響けサンバ
Town is bongo, sound the samba
踊れ南のカルナバル
dance the southern carnival
夢のように 時は過ぎて
Time passes like a dream
はずむ南の恋の夜
bouncing southern night of love
焼けた素肌 肩を抱いて
Tanned skin, hold my shoulders
愛をささやき踊れば
if we whisper love and dance
白い渚に 恋も輝き
Love shines on the white beach
風に誘われ歌いだす
invited by the wind and start singing
オーレ オーレ
Ole ole
マツケンサンバ
Matsuken Samba
オーレ オーレ
Ole ole
マツケンサンバ
Matsuken Samba
ああ 恋せよアミーゴ 踊ろうセニョリータ
Ah, fall in love amigo, let's dance senorita
眠りさえ忘れて 踊り明かそう
Forget even sleep and dance the night away
サンバ ビバ サンバ
Samba, viva Samba
マツ・ゲン・サンバ
Matsu-ken Samba
オレ！
Ole!
一緒にいられて幸せ
Happy to be together
叱られちゃうのも好き好き
I also like being scolded
笑顔がないのも素敵よ
Even without a smile it's wonderful
私の願いを叶えて
please grant my wish
しましょ！しましょ！しましょ！ ハホゥ
Let's do it! Let's do it! Let's do it! Haho
しましょしましょしましょしましょしましょ
Let's do it, do it, do it, do it, let's do it!
初めての
For the first time
あの日の鼓動
the heartbeat of that day
いつまでも感じてたいの
I want to feel it forever
どこまでもあなたと
Wherever I am with you
二人きりで
just the two of us
何にでもときめきたい
I want to be excited about everything
ねえ 恋した人って誰でも
Hey, everyone who falls in love
魔法使いだよね
is a wizard, right?
ねえ 何気ないことにでも
Hey, even for casual things
喜べるのよ
I can be happy
一緒にいられて幸せ
Happy to be together
叱られちゃうのも好き好き
I also like being scolded
笑顔がないのも素敵よ
Even without a smile it's wonderful
私の願いを叶えて
please grant my wish
しましょ！しましょ！しましょ！ ハホゥ
Let's do it! Let's do it! Let's do it! Haho
しましょしましょしましょしましょしましょ
Let's do it, do it, do it, do it, let's do it!
初めては
The first time
陽だまりの中
was in the sunshine
優しくチュッて
You gave me a gentle
してくれたね
peck, didn't you?
唇と唇が
Lips and lips
近づいて
approaching
私は背伸びしたのに
even though I stretched my toes
ねぇ　どうしてあなた　いきなり　逃げ出しちゃうのね
Hey, why do you suddenly run away?
私に振り向いてよ　夢の中だもん
Turn toward me, it's just a dream
一緒にいるのに　なぜなぜ　あなたは私を見ないの
Even though we're together, why don't you look at me?
こんなにこんなに好きでも　願いは叶わないのね
No matter how much I love you, my wish won't come true
嫌い　嫌い　嫌い　本当だよ
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, it's true
嫌い　嫌い　嫌い　本当だもん
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, really
嫌い　嫌い　嫌い　嫌い　だい嫌い
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I really hate you
ねぇ　大好きだよって本当は　囁きたいのね
Hey, I actually want to whisper "I love you"
いつの日か私たち　結ばれるのよね
Someday we will be together, right?
一緒にいられて幸せ　叱られちゃうのも好き好き
I'm happy to be with you, I even like being scolded
笑顔がないのも素敵よ　私の願いを叶えて
Even when you're not smiling, it's wonderful
しましょ　しましょ　しましょ　ハホッ
Let's do it, let's do it, let's do it, hah-hoh
しましょ　しましょ　しましょ　しましょ　はじめてしましょ
Let's do it, let's do it, let's do it, let's start for the first time
はい、ということで、マツケンサンバⅡと「はじめてしましょ」聴いてもらいましたけれども
Yes, so, we've just heard "Matsuken Samba II" and "Hajimete Shimasho"
ね、あの、ころねすきーがなんとついに3Dの体を手に入れました！
And, well, Koronesuki has finally gotten a 3D body!
あのね、前のだいぶ前の歌枠で、なんかマツケンサンバ一緒に3Dで歌おうねみたいに約束したの覚えてる？みんな
You know, in a singing stream a long time ago, I promised we'd sing "Matsuken Samba" together in 3D. Do you guys remember?
それがね、今日なんと、約束が果たせました。楽しかった？
And today, that promise has been fulfilled. Did you have fun?
あ、楽しかったみたいだよ。せっかく、だからちょっとね、撮影しようか？ちょっとみんなで
Ah, it looks like he had fun. Since we're here, why don't we take some photos together?
あ、ちょっとそっち向いてるんだよね、みんなね。
Ah, everyone's looking that way, right?
そしたらじゃあ、まずじゃあ、ピースする？ピース。
In that case, first, shall we do a peace sign? Peace.
顔がでかいな、ちょっと本人がちょっと前出たほうがいい。
His face is huge, it's better if he stands a bit further forward.
あ、撮れた？みんな。撮れたー？
Ah, did you get it? Everyone. Did you get it?
じゃあ、ちょっと抱きしめてもらおうかな？
Then, maybe I'll have him give me a hug?
じゃあ、ころねすきーに抱きしめてもらいます。
Alright, I'll have Koronesuki hug me.
ちょっとやっぱ怪物みたいだね、ころねすきーね、ちょっとね。
He really does look a bit like a monster, Koronesuki, doesn't he?
ということで、えっと、次の曲もありますので、このころねすきーにはね、やっぱ前で見てもらおうかな。
Anyway, um, there's another song, so I'll have this Koronesuki watch from the front.
はい、ありがとうね。一緒に踊ってくれて。ありがとう！
Okay, thank you. For dancing with me. Thank you!
ということで、ころねすきーと一緒に歌った2曲でした。次の曲
So, those were the two songs I sang with Koronesuki. The next song...
聞いてください。このまま行きます。
Please listen. I'll go straight into it.
このまま　歩き続けてる
Continuing to walk like this
今夜も明日も　1人の足跡
Tonight and tomorrow too, a solitary footprint
辿って　果てしない　だけど君だけは
Tracing it, it's endless, but only you
どこかで待ってる　笑顔絶やさずに
Are waiting somewhere, without losing your smile
Believe...
Be the one, be the one, Alright!
明日の地球を　投げ出せないから
Because I can't give up on tomorrow's Earth
Be the light, be the light, Alright!
強くなれるよ　愛は負けない
I can become stronger, love won't lose
何かを助け　救って抱きしめ
Helping something, saving and embracing
心に触れて　届くよ伝われ
Touching the heart, reaching out, let it be conveyed
Be the one, be the light, メッセージ送るよ
Be the one, be the light, I'll send a message
響くよ
It will resonate
何より　大事な出来事
More than anything, an important event
生きてる今夜も　必ず前に
Living tonight too, definitely forward
進まなきゃいけない
I have to move forward
昨日より　強さと優しさ
More than yesterday, strength and kindness
大人になってる
I'm becoming an adult
みんな感じてる　J-U-W-E-L
Everyone is feeling it, J-U-W-E-L
Be The One, Be The One, We will
必ず夜明けは巡ってくるから
Because the dawn will surely come around
Be The Light, Be The Light, We will
未来へつなごう　過去をいたわろう
Let's connect to the future, let's cherish the past
現代を生きよう　そして忘れない
Let's live the present and not forget
奇跡と偶然　太陽と月
Miracles and coincidences, the sun and the moon
Be The One, Be The Light
メッセージ届くよ
The message will reach you
刻むよ
I'll engrave it
Be The One, Be The One, We will
make all your sight we'll be the one
Be The Light, Be The Light
We'll take darkness into brightness yeah
Leading you into the light, Be the Light
Oh you will be alive
Be The One, Be The One
You will be the one
We'll make a way
Na na na na na na na na na na na na...
ギラギラ容赦ない太陽が
The relentless, blazing sun
強気で照りつける On the beach
Shines down boldly on the beach
うぬぼれ温度は急上昇
The conceit temperature is rising rapidly
落ち着かないのは 真夏の性だな
Being restless is just the nature of midsummer
ふたり 目が合えば なぜか 逸らすのに
When our eyes meet, for some reason you look away
僕は またすぐ見てしまう 君のこと
But I'm looking at you again immediately
もしかして もしかして
Could it be, could it be
フライングゲット 僕は一足先に
Flying Get, I'll be one step ahead
君の気持ち 今すぐ手に入れようか
Shall I take hold of your feelings right now?
フライングゲット 何か言われる前に
Flying Get, before anything is said
心のうちは ビビッと感じたままに
Feeling the spark in my heart as it is
誰がいても 誰がいても 微笑み方に
No matter who's there, no matter who's there, in the way you smile
君が僕に 恋をしてるのは明確
It's clear that you're in love with me
フライングゲット だから 誰より早く
Flying Get, so faster than anyone else
君のハートのすべて 僕のものさ
The whole of your heart belongs to me
好きだから
Because I love you
ラブ・フラゲ！
Love Flage!
クラクション鳴らした順序で
In the order the horns were honked
砂浜歩いてた ビキニ
The bikini walking on the sandy beach
告白ウェルカム さあおいで
Confession welcome, come on over
素直にならなきゃ 楽しくないぜ
If you're not honest, it's no fun
不意に誘ってる 僕を見て
Suddenly inviting, look at me
期待させて
Giving me expectations
それなら 妄想したって 声を
In that case, even if I fantasize, a voice...
かけてみなきゃ 始まらない
...if I don't try calling out, it won't start
フライングゲット 君に空振りしても
Flying Get, even if I swing and miss with you
当たって砕けろ 男じゃないか
Go for broke, aren't you a man?
フライングゲット いつも やりたい放題
Flying Get, always doing whatever I want
黙って見てても 恋は売り切れるよ
Even if you watch in silence, love will be sold out
勇み足でも 勇み足でも 一番乗りで
Even if overeager, even if overeager, being the first to arrive
僕と君に そこそこなのは 不相応
Something average for you and me is unfitting
フライングゲット ようやく 待ってたような
Flying Get, finally, it seems I've been waiting
周りの男たちを 出し抜いて
Outsmarting the men around you
得意げに
Proudly
ラブ・フラゲ！
Love Flage!
フライングゲット 僕は一足先に
Flying Get, I'll be one step ahead
君の気持ち 今すぐ手に入れようか
Shall I take hold of your feelings right now?
フライングゲット
Flying Get
（歌唱：フライングゲット）
(Singing: Flying Get)
あははは…
Ahahaha...
聞いてくれてありがとう！
Thanks for listening!
まぁね、言いたいことはあるよね。
Well, there's something we want to say, right?
ある！
There is!
ころねおめでとうじゃないの、言いたいこと。
It's not just "Happy Birthday, Korone."
あの…最初と最後のさ、あの「ふぅ」ってやつ。
That... that "fuu" sound at the beginning and end.
ラミィだよね！なんで歌わないの！
It was Lamy, right! Why didn't you sing!
なんでラミィだよ！なんでラミィなんだよ！
Why me! Why is it always me!
いやそこ歌わないの、凄かった。
No, you not singing there was amazing.
ま、でもノエルが言ってるから、ノエルに任せておこうかって。
Well, since Noel was doing it, I thought I'd leave it to her.
なるほどね…
I see...
見せ場、見せ場。
A highlight, a highlight.
素敵、素敵なプレゼントもらったよ。
I got a wonderful, wonderful present.
お誕生日…
Happy...
おめでとう！
Birthday!
せっかく、せっかくやからね、
Since we're all here together,
みんなと写真を撮りたいなと思って。
I thought I'd like to take a photo with everyone.
撮りたい！撮ろう！
I want to! Let's do it!
真ん中でね。
In the middle.
他になんかしたいことないんですか？
Is there anything else you want to do?
ここやっぱりさ、この砂浜よ、砂浜。
After all, it's this beach, the beach.
綺麗だよね。
It's beautiful, isn't it?
あはは待って、みたいな。
Like, "Ahaha, wait for me."
追いかけっこしたいなと思って。
I thought I'd like to play tag.
追いかけっこ！砂浜だからね！
Tag! Because it's a beach!
あ！なんかちょうどここに枝が！
Oh! There's a stick right here!
枝なんて落ちてるの！
A stick is just lying here!
よっしゃ、これ。行くよ！
Alright, this one. Here I go!
こい！
Come and get it!
はぁ、みんな帰っちゃった。
Phew, everyone's gone.
ちょっとね、ころねはこのあと、
In a bit, Korone is going to
普通のね、お洋服に着替えてくるんだけど、
change into regular clothes, but
その前にちょっとあの、すごいやりたかったことがあって、
before that, there's something I really wanted to do,
その動画を運営さんがすごい頑張って作ってくれたのがあるから、
the staff worked really hard to make a video of it,
それをみんなちょっと見てて待っててください。
so everyone, please watch that and wait for me.
ちょっとお着替えしてくるから、見てて待っててね！
I'm going to change, so watch and wait!
戌神ころね　イチゴのショートケーキ
Inugami Korone - Strawberry Shortcake
恋のカーニバル招待状が届いたよ
An invitation to the Carnival of Love has arrived
ポニピュッピュッピュッ　トゥンピークンピー
パンピピンプー　トゥンピークンピー
Ponipyu ppyu ppyu tumpikunpi
Panpimpinpu tumpikunpi
ミミズさんがお出迎え
Mr. Earthworm welcomes you
気持ち悪い
Disgusting
ポニピュッピュッピュッ　トゥンピークンピー
パンピピンプー　トゥンピークンピー
Ponipyu ppyu ppyu tumpikunpi
Panpimpinpu tumpikunpi
きれいなシャンデリア
A beautiful chandelier
タコさんウィンナー食べ放題
All-you-can-eat octopus sausages
爪楊枝は刺さってますか？
Are the toothpicks stuck in?
ダンゴムシは放し飼い
The pill bugs are free-range
踏みつぶしますよ
I'll crush them
Ah　ジャーマネほしい
Ah, I want a manager
立候補しますよ～
I'll run for office~
チョコレートのケーキを食べたの
I ate a chocolate cake
お腹の中が
Inside my stomach is
トリトントン　タンラントティントン
Toritonton tanrantotiinton
イチゴのショートケーキを食べたの
I ate a strawberry shortcake
お腹の中が
Inside my stomach is
トリトントン　タンラントティントン
Toritonton tanrantotiinton
トリトントンってわけわかランボルギーニ！
Toritonton makes no sense, Lambor-whatever!
今年で36歳
36 years old this year.
後がないですよ〜
There's no turning back now~
挑戦し続ける姿は
The sight of her continuing to challenge herself...
まさに三つ編みのジャンヌダルクですね
...is truly the Joan of Arc of braids.
光のさす方へ 走り続け
Keep running towards where the light shines.
時には立ち止まってもいいさ
It's okay to stop and rest sometimes.
君は一人じゃない
You are not alone.
共に手を取り合い さぁゴールしよう
Let's take each other's hands and reach the goal.
急になんですか？
What was that all of a sudden?
チョコレートのケーキを食べたの
I ate a chocolate cake.
お腹の中が
Inside my stomach...
トリトントン タンタントティーントーン
Tori-tonton, tan-tan-to-tiin-toon.
イチゴのショートケーキを食べたの
I ate a strawberry shortcake.
お腹の中が
Inside my stomach...
トリトントン タンタントティーントーン
Tori-tonton, tan-tan-to-tiin-toon.
トリトントンて わけわかランボルギーニ!
Tori-tonton? I don't get it, Lamborghini!
フフフフン!
Hm-hm-hm-hmmm!
はい、着替えてきました！
Alright, I'm back and changed!
ということでね あの みんなも察してると思うけど
So, as I'm sure you've all guessed...
誕生日グッズが出ました こちら、ドーン！
...birthday merchandise is out! Here it is, ta-da!
はい、どうもー！
Hello there!
お知らせ担当の、こーねでございます！
I'm Kone, in charge of announcements!
今回も誕生日記念グッズ出るじょー、パフパフドンドンドン！
Birthday goods are coming out again! Puff-puff, bang-bang!
今回の生誕祭ライブはですね
For this birthday live...
ダイナーをコンセプトにしておりまして
...we have a 'diner' theme.
それに合わせて誕生日グッズもダイナー仕様となっております
Accordingly, the birthday goods are also diner-style.
1つずつ紹介していきますね
Let me introduce them one by one.
まずはこちら
First, we have this.
ダイナー風B2タペストリー！
Diner-style B2 Tapestry!
この可愛いこーねは フカヒレママに描いてもらったよ
This cute Kone was drawn by Fukahire-mama.
気づいた方もいらっしゃると思うんですけれども
I think some of you might have noticed...
こーねのオリ曲の「Doggy Gods' Street」の衣装を着てます
...I'm wearing my outfit from my original song, 'Doggy Gods' Street'.
なので ダイナーなほーねで働いてる時のこーねかなと思います
So, this is me working at the 'Diner Nahone'.
あー可愛いですね
Ah, how cute.
続いてこちら
Next is this.
フトイヌ＆ホソイヌグラス！
Futoinu & Hosoinu Glasses!
こちらはね、こーねがなんと描き下ろしをしました
I actually drew these illustrations myself.
描き下ろしたって言っても 線をね2、3本描いただけなんですけれども
Though 'drew' might be an overstatement, I just drew a few lines.
ちゃんとね あの フトイヌの方は線が太かったり
But you see, the lines for Futoinu are thick...
ホソイヌは線が細かったりとかして
...and the lines for Hosoinu are thin.
まぁこだわりを感じる逸品でございますね
It's a masterpiece that shows my attention to detail.
続いてこちら
Next up is this.
ころねの部屋着風アロハシャツ！
Korone's Roomwear-style Aloha Shirt!
こーねの部屋着めちゃ可愛いよね
My roomwear is super cute, isn't it?
外用の服も欲しくない？
Don't you want something you can wear outside too?
ってことで作りました
So, I made this.
来年の夏はこれで決まりだね
This will be perfect for next summer.
黄色地に白の模様なので がっつり目立つ感じでもないよね
It's a white pattern on a yellow base, so it's not too loud.
なので着やすいかなと思いますので
I think it'll be easy to wear...
お外でたくさん着てほしいなと思います
...so I hope you'll wear it out a lot.
Doggyプレート！
Doggy Plate!
こちらはね 「Doggy Gods' Street」のMVのこーねのお皿となっております
This is based on the plate from the 'Doggy Gods' Street' MV.
こーねの顔の上に料理を乗せてもよし
You can put food on my face...
飾ってもよしの逸品となっております
...or just display it. It's a fine piece.
今回全部セットを購入していただいた方には
For those who buy the full set...
ダイナーで働くこーねのボイスと 直筆サインがみんなについてきます
...you'll get a special voice recording and a handwritten autograph.
数量限定ではなく 購入した方全員にサインを書きますので
It's not limited in quantity; I'll sign for everyone who buys one.
購入に急がなくても大丈夫でございますので
So, you don't need to rush to buy it immediately.
よろしくお願いいたします
Thank you for your support.
1つずつ運営さんたちとたくさん考えて作ったので
I worked hard with the staff to come up with each of these.
是非お手に取ってもらえたらと思います
I hope you'll consider getting them.
以上、お知らせ担当のこーねでした！
That's all from Kone, the announcement person!
よかったら是非是非ご検討のほどお願いします
Please do consider checking them out if you'd like.
あと、この後すぐですね あの メンバーシップ限定で
Also, right after this, for members only...
二次会みたいなやつをね あの 歌を2曲ぐらい歌いますので
...I'll be doing an after-party and singing two more songs.
そちらも楽しみにしていただけたらと思います
I hope you'll look forward to that as well.
もう寂しいね
It's already getting a bit lonely.
次が最後の曲となってしまいました
The next one is the final song.
皆さん 今日は来てくれてありがとうございました
Everyone, thank you so much for coming today.
ちょっとね こね あの 頭につけるものがあるの
I have something I need to put on my head.
ちょっとみんなそこで待っててください すぐね すぐ始まりますので
So please wait for just a moment. It'll start very soon.
なんか、あれ？
Wait, what's this?
なんか VTRがあるみたいなんですけど
It looks like there's a VTR.
え、今、今やってていいんですか？
Eh, is it okay to play it now?
あ、じゃあ VTRどうぞ！なんだろう
Ah, okay, VTR please! I wonder what it is.
皆さん こんにちは
Hello everyone!
ソニックチームです！
We are the Sonic Team!
去年に引き続き 今年もコメントを出させていただきました！
Following up from last year, we've sent another message this year!
今年はソニックイヤーで ころねさんとのコラボも大きく賑わってますね！
It's the 'Year of Sonic', and the collab with Korone-san is really bustling!
あらためまして お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Once again, happy birthday!
これからも頑張ってください
Please keep up the great work.
さあ、そして 今年も彼からメッセージがあるみたいなので
And now, it looks like there's a message from him again this year...
ご覧ください
...so please take a look.
なんと今年はあのキャラからも...？
Could it be that this year, even from that character...?
VTRどうぞ！
VTR, please!
Happy Birthday ころね！
Happy Birthday, Korone!
元気にやってるか？
Are you doing well?
俺はソニック。
I'm Sonic.
ソニック・ザ・ヘッジホッグだ！
Sonic the Hedgehog!
で、一緒に来てくれたこいつが...
And the guy who came with me is...
ナックルズ。
Knuckles.
ナックルズ・ザ・エキドゥナだ！
Knuckles the Echidna!
まあ、お前はゲームプレイで俺をかっこよく見せてくれたらしいし、
Well, I heard you made me look cool in your gameplay,
ソニステの借りもあるしな。
and I owe you for Soniste, too.
だから、まあ... おめでとさん！
So, well... Happy Birthday!
たく、普通にお祝いを言えばいいのに、
Geez, he could just say it normally,
ナックルズはまわりくどいぜ。
but Knuckles is so roundabout.
相変わらずすごい人気だな！
You're as popular as ever!
今も長い時間配信頑張ってるのか？
Are you still working hard on long streams?
俺なんか同じ場所に10分と居られないから、お前って、ほんとにすごいと思うぜ！
I can't stay in the same place for ten minutes, so I think you're really amazing!
でもあんまり無理はするなよ。
But don't overdo it.
気合と根性にしたって、それはよく寝た頭からわいてくるもんだからな。
Even willpower and guts come from a well-rested head.
今度会ったとき青い顔してやがったら、ぶっとばすぞ！
Next time we meet, if you're looking pale, I'll blow you away!
Hey Knuckles! 素直に体に気をつけて頑張れよって言えよな。
Hey Knuckles! Just say 'Take care of yourself and do your best' honestly.
てなわけで、俺たちからお前に誕生日のお祝いメッセージだ☆
Anyway, here's a birthday message from us to you.
これからも応援よろしくな！
Keep supporting us!
See You~
またな！
See ya!
ソニック、ソニックチームの皆さんとソニックとナックルズ君ありがとう！
Sonic, everyone from Sonic Team, and Sonic and Knuckles, thank you!
ソニックチームの皆さんみんな優しくてね、本当に大好きです。
Everyone at Sonic Team is so kind, I really love them.
これからもお世話になると思うので。
I'm sure I'll be in your care from now on.
え、めっちゃ嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
ちゃんと歌えるかな？ありがとうございました！
I wonder if I can sing properly? Thank you very much!
え？なんかもう一本あるらしい。え？誰？
Eh? It seems there's another one. Eh? Who?
あ、じゃあ、もう一本あるみたいなので、お願いします、どうぞ！
Ah, okay, it looks like there's one more, so please, go ahead!
レベルファイブ日野です。
I'm Hino from Level-5.
ころねさん、10月1日は誕生日ということで、おめでとうございます！
Korone-san, October 1st is your birthday, so congratulations!
こないだやらせてもらったコラボもですね、僕ら大変良い結果をだしておりまして、
The collaboration we did recently also had very good results,
スタッフ一同喜んでおります。
and all our staff are very happy.
これからもですね、仲良くさせていただきたいと思いますので、レベルファイブ共々よろしくお願いします。
We'd like to continue our good relationship, so please support Level-5 as well.
本当におめでとうございます！
Congratulations, truly!
日野社長！え、本物？
President Hino! Eh, the real one?
嘘でしょ！
No way!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
妖怪ウォッチ大好きです。
I love Yo-kai Watch.
妖怪ウォッチ以外も大好きです。ありがとうございます。
I love things other than Yo-kai Watch too. Thank you very much.
嬉しい...ちょっともう言葉が出てきません。
I'm so happy... I can't find the words.
もう歌えないかもしれない。
I might not be able to sing anymore.
ということでじゃあ... え、待って？え？えー！？
And so... Eh, wait? Eh? E-!?
もう一本ある！もう一本あるみたいです。
There's one more! It seems there's one more.
ちょっと待ってまだちょっと紹介しきれてないそのソニックチームと日野社長と。
Wait, I haven't fully processed Sonic Team and President Hino yet.
え、じゃあ... お願いしますどうぞ！紹介しきれないよ。
Eh, well... please, go ahead! I can't process it all.
はじめまして。ドラゴンクエストゲームデザイナーの堀井雄二です。
Nice to meet you. I'm Yuji Horii, the Dragon Quest game designer.
戌神ころねさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます。
Inugami Korone-san, happy birthday.
イェーイ！
Yippie!
ころねさんはDQが好きとのことでプレイしていただきとても嬉しく思っています。
I heard you like DQ, and I'm very happy that you play it.
ころねさんのDQIIIのゲーム配信は見せていただきましたよ。
I watched your Dragon Quest III gameplay stream.
ゲーム内の性格診断テストで、「西に進むべし」と看板に書かれているところで、
In the personality test, where the sign said 'Go West',
西は右側だと思って右に行ったら、落とし穴に落ちてしまいましたね。
you thought West was on the right and went right, falling into a pitfall.
その結果、勇者ころねの性格診断が「わがまま」となってしまいました。
As a result, hero Korone's personality test came out as 'selfish'.
その節は大変失礼いたしました。（もしかして当たっていました？）
I'm very sorry for that. (Or maybe it was accurate?)
他にも洞窟の宝箱でミミックの罠にハマったり、
Also, falling into Mimic traps in treasure chests,
モンスター格闘場で高倍率を当てたりと、とても楽しい配信をありがとうございます。
and winning high odds in the arena, thank you for such fun streams.
DQシリーズはこれまでたくさん出ておりますので、また別のシリーズも遊んでいただきたいですし、
Since there are many titles, I'd like you to play other titles as well.
DQXオンラインや、12月に発売するDQトレジャーズ、
Like Dragon Quest X Offline, or DQ Treasures coming in December,
その先にも色々開発していますので是非遊んでくださいね！
we're developing more, so please play them!
ところで、ころねさんが初めて遊んだDQはVIだと聞きました。
By the way, I heard the first Dragon Quest you played was VI.
なんとここに1995年に発売されたスーパーファミコン版のDQVIの新品ゲームがあります。
Incredibly, I have a brand new copy of the SNES version of DQVI released in 1995.
これをプレゼントしたいと思います。
I'd like to give this to you as a gift.
堀井さん、それに堀井さんのサインをころねさん宛に書いていただくことってできますかね？
Horii-san, could you also sign that for Korone-san?
いいですよ。あ、じゃあ書きましょうか。はい。
Sure. Ah, then shall I write it? Yes.
やったー！ころねさんやりましたよ！
Awesome! Korone-san, we did it!
緊張します。
I'm nervous.
えっ、嘘でしょ！
Wait, no way!
Wait, you're kidding!
えっ、待って、えっ...
Wait, hold on, what...?
はぁ、堀井さんのスライム...
Haa, it's Horii-san's Slime...
嘘でしょ！
No way!
日付とか入れたほうがいいですよね。
It's better to include the date, right?
はい。
Yes.
じゃあ、2022年10月1日...
Then, October 1st, 2022...
...2022年10月1日。
...October 1st, 2022.
はい、できました。
All right, it's done.
えー！
Whoa!
ご覧です。
Here it is.
これからも笑顔いっぱいの楽しい配信を楽しみにしています。
I look forward to more fun streams full of smiles from now on.
それでは、ゆびゆび～
Now then, Yubi Yubi~
ゆびゆび～
Yubi Yubi~
堀井雄二でした。
This was Yuji Horii.
嘘、え、あははは、ええええ、ちょっと待って！堀井さんが持ってる、本物だよ、すご！
No way, wait, ahahaha, whoa, hold on! Horii-san is holding it, it's real, amazing!
え、これ堀井さんが触ったやつですか？
Wait, is this the one Horii-san touched?
あの...電脳空間にあります、この、え、すごい、待って！
Um... it's here in the digital space... this... whoa, amazing, wait!
えっ、しかも、なんか、え、あれ運営さん、え、ありがとうございます。
Wait, and also... um, is that the staff? Thank you so much.
で、あの、見えてないと思うけど、これ持っ... え、嬉しい！
And, um, you probably can't see it, but I'm holding... oh, I'm so happy!
あの、え、ちょっと待って、気さくに話しかけてたのは運営さんですか？
Um, wait a second, was it the staff talking so casually?
あの、堀井、堀井さんに。え、誰、誰ですか？
To Horii-san. Who, who was that?
スクウェア・エニックス、ドラゴンクエストシリーズ
Square Enix, Dragon Quest series...
チーフプロデューサーの藤本さん、ちょっと待って、どっちもすごい方だったんですけど！
Chief Producer Fujimoto-san... wait a minute, both of them were such incredible people!
えっと、堀井さん、藤本さん、ありがとうございました！
Um, Mr. Horii, Mr. Fujimoto, thank you so much!
そして、運営さん、え、ありがとうございます。え...
And staff, thank you so much. Um...
サプライズ...
A surprise...
嬉しい、ちょっと待って、歌えないかもしれないです。
I'm so happy... wait, I might not be able to sing.
え、でも歌ったほうがいいんですよね？
Wait, but I should sing, right?
これで終わりじゃない。これ、これ持ってる、今。ありがとうございます、本当に。
This isn't the end. I have... I'm holding this now. Thank you so much, truly.
ドラゴンクエスト、最高！
Dragon Quest is the best!
妖怪ウォッチ最高！
Yo-kai Watch is the best!
ソニック最高！
Sonic is the best!
じゃあ、え、ちょっと歌えないかも。どうしよう。
Then, um... I might not be able to sing. What should I do?
Doggy god's street
作詞：TOPHAMHAT-KYO (FAKE TYPE.)
作曲：DYES IWASAKI (FAKE TYPE.)
Doggy god's street
Lyrics: TOPHAMHAT-KYO (FAKE TYPE.)
Composition: DYES IWASAKI (FAKE TYPE.)
1 2 3 の飯 戌神どきめいちゃどっくなぶっしー
1 2 3, meal! Inugami Doggy, crazy doggy beat.
かなりお転婆 かなりハッピー の竹鳥チクローザー
Quite a tomboy, quite happy, Taketori Chiku-closer.
キャハピでコール！らぶれもん！ みんなまとめて仲間とアフレコ！
Kyapapi call! Love lemon! Everyone together, voice-over with friends!
ほら尾ひねってごきげんよう お船で女子いいねおもし
Look, twist your tail, greetings! Girls on a boat, nice and heavy.
もう十分せめー。くし。 どっすーらが。おーば。
It's enough, narrow. Comb. Dossura. Over.
Inside から West Side わな。のーば。りの。から。
Inside to West Side, trap. No-ba. Rino. From.
もちもちきり。え。 さしくぶっ飛ばす。
Mochi-mochi cut. Eh. Sashiku, blow them away.
レッツノーマイル。ね。ね。 ころね。Oh Yeah!
Let's No Mile. Ne ne. Korone. Oh Yeah!
Oh! Get out of my way Hi! Hi! Oh! 美味しく完食
Oh! Get out of my way! Hi! Hi! Oh! A delicious finish.
Oh! Yeah! Hi! Sure な Party
Oh! Yeah! Hi! A sure party.
Hi! Hi! Oh! お利口上等
Hi! Hi! Oh! Being a good girl is top tier.
Wow wow wow Loud up town Watch out りのままさ
Wow wow wow, Loud up town, watch out, just as Rino is.
Wow wow wow Go go go ブルなこの生き様
Wow wow wow, Go go go, this bull-like way of life.
サンダラ。な。サンシャイン。 ワッチャ。すぐ。かがやく。
Thundara. Sunshine. Watcha. Soon to shine.
絶対。敵。レゲ。レ。な。 おった。どっぎー。がっど。
Absolute. Enemy. Reggae. Found it. Doggy. God.
世界中席巻 警告計画 年柄年中 Enjoy 楽天
Conquering the world, Warning Plan, enjoying optimism all year round.
万倍のピースを Effect 皆バラ グッショロトゥルース ミナミーゴスドップ
Ten thousand times the peace, Effect everyone, Good-shoro-truth, Minamigos-dopp.
ドマチカナイバナイ シャカリキパフォーマー ギットアップでエブリババ
Domachikanaibanai, Shakariki performer, Get up with everybaba.
非表示はだめ 廃犬のようさ North Side から South Side
No hiding, like a stray dog, from North Side to South Side.
まで漏らすよ奴ら
Those guys will leak it all.
どちどちきり 風のようさ飛ばす
Doki-doki cut, flying like the wind.
レッツノーマイル。ね。ね。 ころね。Oh Yeah!
Let's No Mile. Ne ne. Korone. Oh Yeah!
Oh! Get out of my way Hi! Hi! Oh! 美味しく完食
Oh! Get out of my way! Hi! Hi! Oh! A delicious finish.
Oh! Yeah! Hi! Sure な Party
Oh! Yeah! Hi! A sure party.
Hi! Hi! Oh! お利口上等
Hi! Hi! Oh! Being a good girl is top tier.
Wow wow wow Loud up town Watch out りのままさ
Wow wow wow, Loud up town, watch out, just as Rino is.
Wow wow wow Go go go ブルなこの生き様
Wow wow wow, Go go go, this bull-like way of life.
サンダラ。な。サンシャイン。 ワッチャ。すぐ。かがやく。
Thundara. Sunshine. Watcha. Soon to shine.
絶対。敵。レゲ。レ。な。 おった。どっぎー。がっど。
Absolute. Enemy. Reggae. Found it. Doggy. God.
Alright 鎖に繋がれるなんて真っ平御免あそばせ
Alright, being chained up is the last thing I'd want, excuse me.
不意の一発で実家の鼓動もしらばっちょがめちゃカオス
A sudden strike makes even home's heartbeat go crazy chaos.
氷結ドギー 嗅ぎのドギー 下そうさ 揺りのりのりのりのり
Frozen Doggy, Sniffing Doggy, it's a letdown, swaying around.
一回喝破 放たれる Doggy God You can go bye bye
One shout out, unleashing Doggy God! You can go bye bye.
Doggy Doggy God
Doggy doggy god
当然今日も新記録
Naturally, today is also a new record
Doggy doggy god
Clap your hands, wag your tail
Rollin' rollin' down
Bow-wow-wow, la-la-down, watcha gonna do, master?
Bow-wow-wow, na-na-down
変なこだわり刻ま
Carving out strange fixations
トンデラまわさない
Tondera, won't turn it
ワンチャンスで輝け
Shine in that one chance
絶対的レギュラー
An absolute regular
ワンダー・ドギー・ガッド
Wonder Doggy God
遅れた...だけど
3Dライブ、すごく楽しかったよ!!
It was late... but
the 3D live was so much fun!!
待っててくれた みんな
たくさんがんばってくれた 運営さん
Everyone who waited for me
and the staff who worked so hard
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
来年もまた、
みんなでお祝いできますように...
Next year as well,
I hope we can celebrate together...